Guide to the Yale Student Composers Interviews
Yale Student Composers Interviews
Oral History of American Music
Yale Student Composers Interviews
2010 2021
OHVII
Oral History of American Music
94 Computer Files
249.7 gigabytes
General
69 interviews as of September 9, 2021. OHAM regularly conducts new interviews to add to this collection.
Scope and Contents
The Yale Student Composers project documents Yale's celebrated graduate student composers. These promising young artists are interviewed at the outset of their studies at Yale, and they speak about their work, musical education, inspiration, and other subjects. Their testimony is filmed by a professional videographer.
Separated Materials
The following interviews, originally in this collection, have been moved to Major Figures of American Music (OHV): Cerrone, Chris - OHVII 1 a (now OHV 410); Adams, Samuel - OHVII 2 a (now OHV 411).
Accruals
OHAM conducts interviews to add to this collection on a yearly basis.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. The finding aid includes links to stream most interviews online via Oral History of American Music's (OHAM) AV access system, Aviary. Yale users can login to Aviary using their Yale University ID, to stream these interviews without restriction. Other users are able to request access to interviews directly through Aviary. For access instructions, and to request transcripts of an interview, see OHAM's website. This finding aid also includes links to Table of Contents for most interviews.
Some interviews may be restricted. Access to these restricted interviews may only be granted to a patron who has first obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
Some interviews may not have been digitized or are otherwise not available to stream online. However, these interviews may have been transcribed. Please see contact OHAM for more details.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname of interviewee.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
.mov, .mp4 and .wav files
Composers United States; Yale University Students; Yale School of Music
- Akiho, Andy
  - Akiho, Andy, 2011 March 30; OHVII 13 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 30 mins
    Interview Location
    New Haven, CT
    Akiho, Andy
- Auznieks, Krists
  - Auznieks, Krists, 2015 February 25; OHVII 35 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 21 mins
    Auznieks, Krists
- Balch, Katherine
  - Balch, Katherine, 2015 February 24; OHVII 32 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 17 mins
    Balch, Katherine
- Banks, Diallo
  - Banks, Diallo, 2024 March 4; OHVII 78 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 1.1 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 17 mins
    Interview location
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    .mp4 file
    Banks, Diallo
- Benton, Brittney
  - Benton, Brittney, 2024 March 4; OHVII 79 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 1.2 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 19 mins
    Benton, Brittney
- Braun, Ethan
  - Braun, Ethan, 2016 March 7; OHVII 38 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 21 mins
    Braun, Ethan
- Bridgham, Matthew
  - Bridgham, Matthew, 2016 March 7; OHVII 40 a; Rhodes, Anne, 1976-; Approximate Running Time: 15 mins
    Bridgham, Matthew
- Cash-Goldwasser, Sophie
  - Cash-Goldwasser, Sophie, 2017 June 3; OHVII 44 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 20 mins
    Cash-Goldwasser, Sophie
- Čudars, Matīss
  - Čudars, Matīss, 2022 March 4; OHVII 69 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 560 megabytes; Approximate running time: 38 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in New Haven, CT and interviewer in Guilford, CT.
    Conditions Governing Access
    As a preservation measure, original computer files may not be used. Digital access copies must be provided for use.
    Čudars, Matīss
- Dallimore, Linda
  - Dallimore, Linda, 2021 April 12; OHVII 67 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 208 megabytes; Approximate running time: 33 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee located in Auckland, New Zealand and inteviewer located in Guilford, CT. (Due to time difference, date in New Zealand was April 13, 2021.)
    Dallimore, Linda
- DiBerardino, Nicholas
  - DiBerardino, Nicholas, 2014 February 19; OHVII 29 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 23 mins
    DiBernardino, Nick
- Dietterich, Natalie
  - Dietterich, Natalie, 2015 February 25; OHVII 37 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 23 mins
    Dietterich, Natalie
- Eimold, Forrest
  - Eimold, Forrest, 2023 March 6; OHVII 72 a; Van't Hoff, Lloyd; 1 Computer File; 1.19 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 18 mins
    Eimold, Forrest
- Esmail, Reena
  - Esmail, Reena, 2011 March 30; OHVII 14 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 23 mins
    Esmail, Reena, 1983-
- Evans, Fjola
  - Evans, Fjola, 2017 June 3; OHVII 42 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 21 mins
    Evans, Fjóla
- Fabris, Anteo
  - Fabris, Anteo, 2018 March 27; OHVII 50 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate running time: 27 mins.
    Fabris, Anteo
- Feigenbaum, Stephen
  - Feigenbaum, Stephen, 2012 February 29; OHVII 16 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 28 mins
    Feigenbaum, Stephen, 1989-
- Frerer, Jack
  - Frerer, Jack, 2021 March 19; OHVII 64 a; Gancz, Michael; 1 Computer File; 260 megabytes; Approximate running time: 20 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with both interviewee and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    Frerer, Jack
- Fueyo, Julián
  - Fueyo, Julián, 2022 May 10; OHVII 71 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 667 megabytes; Approximate running time: 33 mins
    Fueyo, Julián, 1996-
- Gardiner, William
  - Gardiner, William, 2012 February 29; OHVII 18 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 25 mins
    Gardiner, William, 1987-
- Gezgin, Alishan
  - Gezgin, Alishan, 2017 June 3; OHVII 45 a; Rhodes, Anne, 1976-; Approximate Running Time: 19 mins
    Gezgin, Alishan
- Gilbertson, Michael
  - Gilbertson, Michael, 2012 February 29; OHVII 17 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 23 mins
    Gilbertson, Michael, 1987-
- Gottlieb, Ian
  - Gottlieb, Ian, 2014 February 19; OHVII 28 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 18 mins
    Gottlieb, Ian
- Gusev, Arseniy
  - Gusev, Arseniy, 2023 March 6; OHVII 73 a; Van't Hoff, Lloyd; 1 Computer File; 1.61 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 27 mins
    Gusev, Arseniy
- Greenhoe, Eli
  - Greenhoe, Eli, 2017 June 3; OHVII 43 a; Rhodes, Anne, 1976-; Approximate Running Time: 19 mins
    Greenhoe, Eli, 1994-
- Haaksma, Luke
  - Haaksma, Luke, 2023 March 6; OHVII 74 a; Van't Hoff, Lloyd; 1 Computer File; 1.24 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 21 mins
    Haaksma, Luke
- Hare, Dayton
  - Hare, Dayton, 2023 March 6; OHVII 75 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 1.12 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 18 mins
    Hare, Dayton
- Heim, Brian
  - Heim, Brian, 2015 February 24; OHVII 33 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 18 mins
    Heim, Brian
- Herbst, Gabriel
  - Herbst, Gabriel, 2019 March 6; OHVII 55 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running time: 27 mins
    GABI (Musician)
- Holloway, Michael
  - Holloway, Michael, 2013 March 6; OHVII 21 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 24 mins
    Holloway, Michael R.
- Jani, Sophia
  - Jani, Sophia, 2021 March 12; OHVII 61 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 159 megabytes; Approximate running: 29 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee in Munich, Germany, and interviewer in Guilford, CT.
    mp4 file
    Jani, Sophia
- Joyce, Molly
  - Joyce, Molly, 2016 March 7; OHVII 41 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 22 mins
    Joyce, Molly, 1992-
- Karosi, Balint
  - Karosi, Balint, 2013 March 6; OHVII 22 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 24 mins
    Karosi, Bálint, 1979-
- Kerekes, Paul
  - Kerekes, Paul, 2010 October 20; OHVII 5 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 15 mins
    Kerekes, Paul
  - Kerekes, Paul, 2013 March 27; OHVII 5 b; Van Cleve, Libby
- Kim, Soomin
  - Kim, Soomin, 2021 April 9; OHVII 66 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File (.tif); 134 megabytes; Approximate running time: 22 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee located in New Haven, CT and interviewer located in Guilford, CT.
    Kim, Soomin
- Knight, Adrian
  - Knight, Adrian, 2011 March 30; OHVII 11 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 34 mins
    Knight, Adrian, 1987-
- Koslow, Lily
  - Koslow, Lily, 2024 March 4; OHVII 80 a; Stevens, Will (Oboist); 1 Computer File; 1.49 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 25 mins
    Koslow, Lily
- Kuspa, Jordan
  - Kuspa, Jordan, 2011 March 30; OHVII 10 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 15 mins
    Kuspa, Jordan
- Lamb, Alexis
  - Lamb, Alexis, 2019 March 6; OHVII 53 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 27 mins
    Lamb, Alexis C.
- Lamb, Alexis and Pollock, Frances
  - Lamb, Alexis and Pollock, Frances, 2021 May 7; OHVII 68 a-b; Van Cleve, Libby; 2 Computer Files; 1.22 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 145 mins
    Interview recorded via videochat, with interviewees in New Haven, CT and interviewer in Guilford, CT.
    .mp4 files
    Part b of this interview is restricted until January 1, 2056.
    Pollock, Frances; Lamb, Alexis C.
- Lash, Hannah
  - Lash, Hannah, 2010 November 16; OHVII 9 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 23 mins
    Lash, Hannah, 1981-
- Laurello, Michael
  - Laurello, Michael, 2014 February 19; OHVII 27 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 19 mins
    Laurello, Michael
- Levin, Aaron
  - Levin, Aaron, 2018 March 27; OHVII 51 a; Davis, Marg; Approximate running time: 20 mins.
    Levin, Aaron, 1995-
- Limbacher, Jesse
  - Limbacher, Jesse, 2014 February 19; OHVII 30 a; Valenti, Maura; Limbacher, Jesse, 1991-; Approximate Running Time: 21 mins
- Lindveit, Ryan
  - Lindveit, Ryan, 2018 March 27; OHVII 47 a; Davis, Marg; Approximate running time: 21 mins.
    Lindveit, Ryan
- Liushen, Emily
  - Liushen, Emily, 2023 March 6; OHVII 76 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 1.5 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 25 mins
    Liushen, Emily
- Loiacono, Loren
  - Loiacono, Loren, 2010 October 20; OHVII 8 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 22 mins
    Loiacono, Loren, 1989-
- Luhmann, Grant
  - Luhmann, Grant, 2018 March 24; OHVII 46 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate running time: 25 mins.
    Luhmann, Grant
- Madejek, Kacper
  - Madejek, Kacper, 2024 March 4; OHVII 81 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 1.66 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 27 mins
    Madejek, Kacper
- Mattingly, Dylan
  - Mattingly, Dylan, 2015 February 25; OHVII 36 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 31 mins
    Mattingly, Dylan
- May, Nate
  - May, Nate, 2018 March 27; OHVII 48 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate running time: 36 mins.
    May, Nate
- Meretzky, Lila
  - Meretzky, Lila, 2021 March 5; OHVII 59 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 118 megabytes; Approximate running time: 21 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee in New Haven, CT and interviewer in Guilford, CT
    Meretzky, Lila
- Mortilla, Paul
  - Mortilla, Paul, 2019 March 6; OHVII 58 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate running time: 28 mins
    Interview Location:
    Mortilla, Paul
- Nazaykinskaya, Polina
  - Nazaykinskaya, Polina, 2013 March 6; OHVII 23 a; Kerekes, Paul; Approximate Running Time: 18 mins
    Nazaykinskaya, Polina
  - Nazaykinskaya, Polina, 2013 March 27; OHVII 23 b-i; Van Cleve, Libby
- Neustadter, Garth
  - Neustadter, Garth, 2010 October 20; OHVII 7 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 17 mins
    Neustadter, Garth
- Perlman, Udi
  - Perlman, Udi, 2021 March 19; OHVII 63 a-b; Gancz, Michael; 1 Computer File; 490 megabytes; Approximate running time: 40 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Tel Aviv, Israel, and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    General
    Part a of interview conducted in English, and part b conducted in Hebrew.
    Perlman, Udi
- Pollock, Frances, Davis, Marg
  Pollock, Frances
  - Pollock, Frances, 2018 March 27; OHVII 49 a; Davis, Marg; Approximate running time: 26 mins.
- Porter, Tanner
  - Porter, Tanner, 2018 March 27; OHVII 52 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate running time: 29
    Porter, Tanner
- Purrington, Hilary
  - Purrington, Hilary, 2016 March 7; OHVII 39 a; Rhodes, Anne, 1976-; Approximate Running Time: 15 mins
    Purrington, Hilary
- Ramos, Marco-Adrián
  - Ramos, Marco-Adrián, 2021 March 12; OHVII 60 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 294 magabytes; Approximate running time: 28 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Gravette, AK and interviewer in Guilford, CT
    mp4 files
    Ramos, Marco-Adrián
- Randall-Myers, Brendon
  - Randall-Myers, Brendon, 2013 March 6; OHVII 24 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 23 mins
    Randall-Myers, Brendon
- Rivera, Kyle
  - Rivera, Kyle, 2023 March 6; OHVII 77 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 1.67 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 28 mins
    Rivera, Kyle
- Rogerson, Chris
  - Rogerson, Chris, 2010 October 20; OHVII 4 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 16 mins
    Rogerson, Chris, 1988-
- Rubino, James
  - Rubino, James, 2013 March 6; OHVII 25 a; Kerekes, Paul; Approximate Running Time: 28 mins
    Rubino, James
- Schlosberg, Daniel
  - Schlosberg, Daniel, 2012 February 29; OHVII 20 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 31 mins
- Shin, Peter
  - Shin, Peter, 2019 March 6; OHVII 56 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 25 mins
    Shin, Peter, 1991-
- Steinke, Harriet
  - Steinke, Harriet, 2021 March 12; OHVII 62 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; Approximate running time: 27 mins
    Steinke, Harriet, 1994-
- Surillo, Omar
  - Surillo, Omar, 2011 March 30; OHVII 12 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 29 mins
    Surillo, Omar
- Thompson, Joel
  - Thompson, Joel, 2019 March 6; OHVII 57 a; Thompson, Joel, 1988-; Approximate Running time: 32 mins
- Tierney, Justin
  - Tierney, Justin, 2010 October 20; OHVII 3 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 15 mins
    Tierney, Justin
- Ugay, Liliya
  - Ugay, Liliya, 2015 February 24; OHVII 34 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 18 mins
    Ugay, Liliya
- Wallace, Ben
  - Wallace, Ben, 2013 March 6; OHVII 26 a; Kerekes, Paul; Approximate Running Time: 30 mins
    Wallace, Ben, 1989-
  - Wallace, Ben, 2013 March 27; OHVII 26 b-c; Van Cleve, Libby
- Walter, Miles
  - Walter, Miles, 2019 March 6; OHVII 54 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate running time: 27 mins
    Walter, Miles
- Wang, Fay
  - Wang, Fay, 2012 February 29; OHVII 19 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 24 mins
    Wang, Fay, 1986-
- Webster, Benjamin
  - Webster, Benjamin, 2022 March 4; OHVII 70 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 499 megabytes; Approximate running time: 31 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in New Haven, CT and interviewer in Guildford, CT.
- Welch, Matthew
  - Welch, Matthew, 2012 February 29; OHVII 15 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 25 mins
    Welch, Matthew, 1976-
- Wolf, Samantha
  - Wolf, Samantha, 2021 April 5; OHVII 65 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 166 megabytes; Approximate running time: 31 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in New Haven, CT and interviewer in Guildford, CT
    Wolf, Samantha
- Wohl, Daniel
  - Wohl, Daniel, 2010 October 20; OHVII 6 a; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 21 mins
    Wohl, Daniel, 1980-
- Wu, Zihan
  - Wu, Zihan, 2024 March 4; OHVII 82 a; Stevens, Will (Oboist); Approximate running time: 23 mins
    Wu, Zihan, 2001-
- Zhou, Tiange
  - Zhou, Tiange, 2014 February 19; OHVII 31 a; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 19 mins
    Zhou, Tiange